<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Posts on</title><link>https://alexander-jackson.github.io/posts/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 24 Aug 2024 17:25:00 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alexander-jackson.github.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Postgres Lock Tricks</title><link>https://alexander-jackson.github.io/posts/postgres-lock-tricks/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Aug 2024 17:25:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://alexander-jackson.github.io/posts/postgres-lock-tricks/</guid><description>Postgres is a much loved relational database system that provides solid performance and reliability. However, the concurrency model that it provides (MVCC - multi-version concurrency control) can lead to some interesting observations.
How does MVCC work? Multi-version concurrency control is not a simple system to explain. It&amp;rsquo;s worth reading the Postgres documentation if you&amp;rsquo;re interested in going deeper with it, but this section aims to provide a small overview.
Read Committed Isolation Level This is the default value for transaction isolation in Postgres and the only one we&amp;rsquo;ll be discussing in this article.</description></item><item><title>Overriding Kubernetes HPAs with Rust</title><link>https://alexander-jackson.github.io/posts/overriding-hpas-with-rust/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://alexander-jackson.github.io/posts/overriding-hpas-with-rust/</guid><description>Horizontal Pod Autoscalers (HPAs) are a common concept in the world of Kubernetes. They allow you to specify that your workloads should scale based on various factors, such as their CPU or memory consumption. You can also extend them with custom plugins such as the prometheus-adapter to scale based on Prometheus metrics.
However, sometimes you just want to tell Kubernetes &amp;ldquo;give me more pods&amp;rdquo;.
Perhaps you&amp;rsquo;ve built up a backlog somewhere in the system, such as a processing queue.</description></item></channel></rss>